In tennis, a lot of times you're going to get shots that aren't standardized, that you're not really prepared for unless you play a lot.
And the half volley is one of those shots.
So here's a drill that helps you get the half volley.
You can use a wall, which is great.
But, in this case, your practice partner, in this case it will be me, I'll be throwing the ball to Darren.
So, imagine that you've hit a nice shot, you're coming to the net, or you've hit a nice serve, you're coming to the net, and your opponent hits a ball that drops by your feet.
It bounces up, and you've got to just block it forward.
So that's what this drill is.
So Darren is going to demonstrate.
I'm going to throw it by his feet.
He's just going to block it forward as he comes to the net.
So it's just a way of taking a ball.
You're not really doing much with it.
You're just blocking it forward.
Now, John McEnroe was a master of this shot.
But you have to have it.
It's very apropos in doubles that you're able to block the ball back, because if they volley it at your feet, you've just got to be able to block it right back.
So what you want to do is just use a whole basket of balls.
See how many in a row you can make.
See how many out of 50 you can make, and as the number of balls in practice improves, your results on the court are also going to improve.